## CURRICULUM VITAE ERICK MWIRIGI

<u>erickmbae21@gmail.com</u> +254 711326099

## Professional summary

Experienced Research & Data Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the government relations industry. Skilled in collecting, cleaning, extrapolating, interpreting, visualizing and reporting data to aid in decision making. Organized and timely in providing staff, departmental members, and executive management with reports on specific data findings and their impact on organizational growth and success.

### Experience

### Research Assistant - Internship

June2021 to Present

The National Authority for the Campaign Against Alcohol and Drug Abuse (NACADA)

- Undertaking institutional, local and national qualitative and quantitative surveys,researches and studies.
- Designing and piloting of data collection instruments.
- Analysis,interpretation and visualization of data from surveys using SPSS and R programming language for use in reports.
- Reporting findings to supervisor by writing effective reports.
- Participating in national and international conferences and workshops for sharing research data.

# Field Enumerator - Contract

January 2021 to May 2021

Pula Advisors Ltd

- Visiting sampled clients for yield harvest measurements.
- Using the Comm Care app to capture harvest measurements.
- Reporting and recommending solutions to challenges faced that could affect the quality of data.
- Developing relationship of trust and safe space during data collection exercises with clients.
- Keeping safe custody of company's inventory.

### Credit Analyst -Internship

April 2018 to September 2018

Bimas Microfinance

- Maintening and growing of a healthy credit portfolio through loan administration, management and compliance with policies.
- Ensuring sustainable growth in accounts of an active clientele base through sales of product and services.
- Preparation and presentation of comprehensive, timely and reliable reports to provide information, aid decision making and gauge performance.
- Preparation and maintenance of records and valuables by ensuring that all documents are filed and kept in a systematic manner for easy tracking and retrieval.

#### Attache'

# <u>July 2017 to September 2017</u> County Sacco Society Limited

- Receive cash and cheques for deposit to various accounts accurately.
- Updating members accounts accurately.
- Attending to members enquiries promptly.
- Prepare daily reconciliation report.
- Report any discrepancy to the supervisor as necessary.

#### **Education**

2013 - 2017

University of Nairobi

- Bachelor's degree in Mathematics, Operations Research(Major)
- Certificate of Competence in Data Analysis using Statistical packages; R, MATLAB, STATA, SPSS and Advanced Excel

April 2012 - June 2012

Maralal Computer College

• Computing Skills Certification (MS applications - MS word, MS access, MS excel, MS office, MS powerpoint)

2008 - 2011

Nguviu Boys High School

• Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education.

# Professional skills, competencies and qualities

- Designing of data collection instruments
- Conducting qualitative and quantitative surveys
- Data entry, cleaning and preparation
- Statistical data analysis
- Data analytics and data exploration
- Data visualization
- Data management
- Preparing and writing reports on survey findings
- Presentation skills
- Software applications (SPSS, R, STATA, MATLAB & EXCEL)
- Good interpersonal and intrapersonal skills
- Self-motivated and performance-driven

### Referees

Morris Kamenderi Principal Research Officer The National Authority for the Campaign Against Alcohol and Drug Abuse (NACADA) <a href="mailto:kamenderi@nacada@go.ke">kamenderi@nacada@go.ke</a> 0721396056

Daniel Mbuvi Operations Manager Pula Advisors Limited daniel@pula.io 0727033579

John Eric Murimi Manager, Chuka Branch Bimas Microfinance 0724229395